An Argumentative Co-worker
I have a co-worker that I really hate.
Even when I explain things to her nicely
she replies in a combative
and argumentative manner.
Since I get upset whenever I talk to her,
I now share my messages to her
through other people.
I try to think it's just the way she is,
but whenever I see her, I get upset.
Sometimes my heart even pounds.
So when you see her and your heart pounds,
is she the one suffering or are you?
(Questioner)
I'm the one suffering.
If you're upset at your husband,
will you talk to him
through your mother-in-law?
(Audience Laughter)
I talked to her directly,
but she kept being argumentative.
And I felt like tensions
would only escalate
if we continued
talking to each other.
Is that person a man or a woman?
(Questioner)
a woman.
Is she the one being argumentative,
or are you both being argumentative
towards each other?
Well...(hesitates)
Well, I tried to be cordial at first.
I think she may always talk that way
towards others.
So you talked to her
without thinking much of it,
but then she tried arguing with you,
right?
(Questioner)
Yes.
And you argue back with the person
who started the argument, do you not?
I do.
(Audience Laughter)
Then you two are even.
You would be the better person
by not arguing back
regardless of whether
she started it or not.
(Questionera) Yes.
From your perspective,
Would you prefer being the better person,
or being on the same level as her?
(Questioner) I'd prefer
being the better person
In that case you shouldn't argue back.
Her being argumentative is her business.
You not arguing back is yours.
(Audience Laughter)
(Questioner)
I understand.
If you want to scoop to her level,
argue back.
But if you think
you should be the better person,
what should you think of her?
Think of her
as a lovely person.
Who'd benefit by thinking so?
(Questioner) I'd benefit.
Right
Why wouldn't you do
something that's good for you?
Why would you make yourself
miserable because of her?
And why would you bother
going through others to talk to her?
You are only hurting yourself.
And yet you think
you are being wise
From the way I see it, it is your loss.
So what are you going to do?
( Laughter )
Just gently look at
the argumentative person and smile.
Think to yourself,
"Geez, lady..." and just smile.
Think, "That's just how you talk".
If you argue back at her, who loses?
You lose.
(sunim) Do you understand?
Yes, I do. Thank you.